{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nicosia","incorrectAnswers":["Riga","Dodoma","Port-au-Prince"],"question":"What is the capital city of Cyprus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A crop duster","incorrectAnswers":["A farm sprayer","A bug disperser","A zapper"],"question":"What is the name of the type of aircraft that spreads pesticides on large areas of farmland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Five Gold Rings","incorrectAnswers":["Five Lords a Leaping","Five Drummers Drumming","Five Calling Birds"],"question":"According to the Christmas song what did my true love give to me on the fifth day of Christmas?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roger Moore","incorrectAnswers":["Sean Connery","George Lazenby","Daniel Craig"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in For Your Eyes Only?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Senegal","incorrectAnswers":["Ghana","Togo","Benin"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Mali?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"A Christmas Carol","incorrectAnswers":["The Hound of the Baskervilles","Poirot","Fahrenheit 451"],"question":"Which famous book begins with the line \"Marley was dead, to begin with. There was no doubt about that\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Anne Boleyn","incorrectAnswers":["Mary Queen of Scots","Victoria","Eleanor of Aquitaine"],"question":"Who was the mother of Elizabeth I?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["North America","Southeast Asia","The Middle East"],"question":"Where in the world are lemons originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Shirley Bassey","Sheena Easton","Sheryl Crow"],"question":"Who performed the theme song to the James Bond film Die Another Day?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A Labyrinth","incorrectAnswers":["A Statue","A Child","A Flying Horse"],"question":"In Greek mythology, what did Daedalus construct for Minos?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Love","incorrectAnswers":["Egg","Zilch","Nil"],"question":"What word is used for a score of 0 in a game of tennis?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Seychelles is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Motor Racing","Swimming","Table tennis"],"question":"With which sport is Monica Seles associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the song 'Elevation'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Diamond","incorrectAnswers":["Quartz","Granite","Obsidian"],"question":"What type of rock is the hardest?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1941","incorrectAnswers":["1939","1948","1945"],"question":"What year did the United States enter World War II?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Nepal","Bangladesh","Bhutan"],"question":"In which country is Chennai?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kaa","incorrectAnswers":["Baloo","Shere Khan","King Louie"],"question":"What is the name of the snake in the Disney film The Jungle Book?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Tapetum Lucidum","incorrectAnswers":["Cornea","Photarium","Lerbos"],"question":"Which part of a cat's eye reflects light ?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"2007","incorrectAnswers":["2005","2009","2011"],"question":"No Country for Old Men was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bangladesh","incorrectAnswers":["Malaysia","Thailand","Singapore"],"question":"Chittagong is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Seat Belt","incorrectAnswers":["Cat Eye","Airbag","Crumple Zone"],"question":"What Vehicular Safety Device Was First Pantented By Ej Claghorn?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Maine","incorrectAnswers":["Alaska","Missouri","Texas"],"question":"Which U.S. state borders only one other state?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"1","incorrectAnswers":["0","2","3"],"question":"How many holes are there on a traditional paint pallette?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Helen","incorrectAnswers":["Ariadne","Medea","Penelope"],"question":"In Greek mythology, who did Paris abduct to cause the Trojan war?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Around the World in 80 Days","incorrectAnswers":["Friendly Persuasion","Giant","The King and I"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1956?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Panettone","incorrectAnswers":["Simnal","Victoria Sponge","Roulade"],"question":"What is the name of the cake traditionally eaten in Italy at Christmas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Illinois","incorrectAnswers":["Iowa","Nebraska","Kansas"],"question":"Which state is directly west of Indiana?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"North America","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Saint Kitts and Nevis is on which continent?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cambodia","incorrectAnswers":["Guatemala","Belgium","Iraq"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Angkor Wat?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Austronesian","Afroasiatic","Austroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Chittagonian' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lomé","incorrectAnswers":["Nouakchott","Dili","Maputo"],"question":"What is the capital city of Togo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hiratsuka","incorrectAnswers":["Ōsaka","Kyoto","Yokohama"],"question":"Which city used to be called Suba?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Texas","incorrectAnswers":["California","Florida","Atlanta"],"question":"What is the second largest state in the USA?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Dim Sum","incorrectAnswers":["Pepperpot","Ema Datshi","Kushari"],"question":"Which of these dishes would you most expect to find in China?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Black","Orange","Maroon"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Cuba?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Lone Wolf","incorrectAnswers":["Black Sheep","Han Solo","Alpha Male"],"question":"What is the term for a canis lupus that prefers to live independent of others or leaves its pack?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A Tramp struggles to live in modern industrial society with the help of a young homeless woman.","incorrectAnswers":["A determined Cuban immigrant takes over a drug cartel.","Three policemen investigate a series of murders with their own brand of justice.","A former Roman General seeks revenge against the emperor who murdered his family."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Modern Times?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Tinker","incorrectAnswers":["Winnie the Pooh","One Hundred Years of Solitude","Parade's End"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'George Smiley'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Football","incorrectAnswers":["Cricket","Rugby","Golf"],"question":"What is the UK's most popular sport?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Bill Withers","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Jackson","Luther Vandross","Marvin Gaye"],"question":"Who Had An 80's Hit With The Song 'Just The Two of Us,'? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sesame ","incorrectAnswers":["Sunflower","Chia","Pumpkin"],"question":"Which seed is the basic ingredient for tahini paste?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Farfalle ","incorrectAnswers":["Conchiglie","Rigatoni","Fusilli"],"question":"What type of pasta resembles a bow-tie in shape?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Alexa","incorrectAnswers":["Siri","Cortana","Amazon Assistant"],"question":"Which virtual assistant is produced by Amazon? ","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yemen","incorrectAnswers":["Zambia","Singapore","Timor-Leste"],"question":"Sana'a is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Crème Brûlée ","incorrectAnswers":["Tiramisu","Eton Mess","Pavlova"],"question":"Which Dessert Has A Custard Base And A Burnt Caramelised Top?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Max Planck","incorrectAnswers":["Louis Daguerre","Mahavira","Enrico Fermi"],"question":"Which theoretical physicist developed a theory of quantum physics and discovered energy quanta?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bahrain","incorrectAnswers":["Armenia","Vietnam","Uruguay"],"question":"Manama is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"One Direction","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatles","NWA","Oasis"],"question":"Which band was Niall Horan a member of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Joey","incorrectAnswers":["A Cygnet","A Kid","A Gosling"],"question":"What is the word for a young wallaby?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Drew Barrymore","incorrectAnswers":["Penélope Cruz","Kirsten Dunst","Charlize Theron"],"question":"Which actress has starred in films including E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial and Donnie Darko?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Kuwait","incorrectAnswers":["Israel","Turkey","Saudi Arabia"],"question":"What country was invaded by Iraq in 1990?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hans Christian Andersen","incorrectAnswers":["Beatrix Potter","Søren Kierkegaard","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Thumbelina'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Munich","incorrectAnswers":["Valencia","Budapest","Milan"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Germany?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Radiator","incorrectAnswers":["Little ears","Rings","to cut"],"question":"The pasta radiatori has what meaning in Italian?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"If you build it, he will come.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Frankly, my dear, I don't give a damn.\"","\"I'll get you, my pretty, and your little dog, too!\"","\"Badges? We ain't got no badges! We don't need no badges! I don't have to show you any stinking badges!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Field of Dreams'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A leap","incorrectAnswers":["A nye","A nest","A sloth"],"question":"What is the word for a group of leopards?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Human Nose","incorrectAnswers":["Rhinoceroses","Kidneys","The Moon"],"question":"In what does a rhinologist specialise?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bruce Willis","incorrectAnswers":["John Travolta","Sean Penn","Al Pacino"],"question":"Which actor played the role of John McClane in Die Hard?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Austronesian","incorrectAnswers":["Sino-Tibetan","Indo-European","Austroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Indonesian' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Golf","Figure skating","Motor racing"],"question":"With which sport is Asbel Kiprop associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Hudson","incorrectAnswers":["The Thames","The Amazon","The Mississippi"],"question":"Onto which river did an Airbus A320  make an emergency landing in January 2009, with all 155 people onboard surviving?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"24","incorrectAnswers":["12","30","365"],"question":"How many days will it be before an analogue clock losing 30 minutes a day shows the right time again?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Radio Carbon Dating","incorrectAnswers":["Olfactory Dating","Magnetic Resonance Dating","Natural Decayance Dating"],"question":"What Process Is Used For Dating Ancient Organic Objects?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Shaggs","incorrectAnswers":["Guns N Roses","Nirvana","The Kingsmen"],"question":"Which American rock band has hits including ‘My Pal Foot Foot’ and ‘Gimmie Dat Ding’","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1976","incorrectAnswers":["1964","1990","2009"],"question":"In which year were the first photographs sent from Mars?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jennifer Hudson","incorrectAnswers":["Adriana Barraza","Cate Blanchett","Abigail Breslin"],"question":"Who won the 2006 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Effie White in Dreamgirls?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Titanic","incorrectAnswers":["As Good as It Gets","The Full Monty","Good Will Hunting"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1997?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Led Zeppelin","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatles","The Rolling Stones","Pink Floyd"],"question":"Which rock band's fourth album had no title or name on the cover, but sold millions of copies?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Lima","incorrectAnswers":["Lame","Loan","Love"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter L?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Wilhelm Conrad Roentgen","incorrectAnswers":["Menes","Gregory Pincus","Max Planck"],"question":"Which influential physicist discovered X-rays?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"German Communist philosopher.","incorrectAnswers":["Leader of Soviet Communist Party who pursued reform to open Eastern Europe to democracy.","Diplomat and Renaissance writer considered the father of political science.","Theoretical physicist and one of the pioneers of quantum mechanics."],"question":"Which of the following describes Karl Marx?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Lao Tzu","incorrectAnswers":["Zoroaster","Mao Zedong","Sun Tzu"],"question":"Which influential historical person was the author of Tao Te Ching and founder of Taoism?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Bethlehem","incorrectAnswers":["Jerusalem","Jericho","Babylon"],"question":"The name of which place of biblical significance actually means 'House of Bread''","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kylie Minogue","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Mika","Hikaru Utada"],"question":"Which musician released the studio album 'Fever'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Onion","incorrectAnswers":["Garlic","Potato","Tomato"],"question":"What Is An Allium Cepa?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Pete Sampras","incorrectAnswers":["Roger Federer","Lleyton Hewitt","Andy Roddick"],"question":"Who Won The US Open Men's Tennis Title in 1990 At The Age Of Just 19?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Geoffrey Chaucer","incorrectAnswers":["William Shakespeare","William Wordsworth","John Milton"],"question":"Who was the first person to be buried at Poets' Corner?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hook and loop (or Hook and eye)","incorrectAnswers":["Buckles","Laces","Zippers"],"question":"What do the Amish use to fasten coats and vests?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"New Year's Eve","incorrectAnswers":["Christmas Day","Thanksgiving Day","Independence Day"],"question":"On what annual holiday do an estimated 1 million people gather in New York's Times Square?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Surfing","incorrectAnswers":["Skate Boarding","Skiing","Boxing"],"question":"What sport do the following terms belong to - \"Hotdog & Bottom Trun\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jack Dorsey","incorrectAnswers":["Steve Wozniak","Elon Musk","Bill Gates"],"question":"Who is the founder of Twitter?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Davy Crockett","incorrectAnswers":["Davy Jones","Davy Barrow","Davy Dylan"],"question":"Which frontiersman died at the Alamo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Train","incorrectAnswers":["Boat","Bus","Plane"],"question":"What word completes the 1951 film title \"Strangers on a ___\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Malta","incorrectAnswers":["Cyprus","Greece","Spain"],"question":"Which country was awarded The George Cross, the highest civilian award for bravery bestowed by the British government, in 1942?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Britney Spears","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Alanis Morissette","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, dancer and actress released the song '(You Drive Me) Crazy'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"George Costanza","incorrectAnswers":["Kramer","Elaine Benes","Jerry Seinfeld"],"question":"What is the name of the character played by Jason Alexander on the show 'Seinfeld'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Chicago","incorrectAnswers":["The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers","Gangs of New York","The Pianist"],"question":"Which movie won the Academy Awards for Best Supporting Actress (Catherine Zeta-Jones) and Best Costume Design (Colleen Atwood) in 2002?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dmitry Glukhovsky","incorrectAnswers":["Salman Rushdie","Agatha Christie","Stephenie Meyer"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Metro 2033'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Atmospheric Pressure","incorrectAnswers":["Humidity","Room Temperature","Salt in sea water"],"question":"What is a barometer used to measure?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Motorsports","incorrectAnswers":["Athletics","Golf","Cycling"],"question":"What sport would you associate with The Indianapolis 500?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'His Last Bow'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Malaysia","incorrectAnswers":["Lebanon","Chad","Slovenia"],"question":"Kuala Lumpur is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bacchus","incorrectAnswers":["Janus","Jupiter","Mars"],"question":"Which Roman God was the equivalent of the Greek God Dionysus?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Philippine ","incorrectAnswers":["Mediterranean","Arabian","Caribbean"],"question":"What is the world's largest sea?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Wet Wet Wet","incorrectAnswers":["Feeder","Wham!","Culture Club"],"question":"Who had 90's hits with 'Julia Says' & 'If I Never See You Again'? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mosquito","incorrectAnswers":["Fly","Tick","Flea"],"question":"Which insect transmits dengue fever, encephalitis and dog heartworm?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lithography","incorrectAnswers":["Stenography","Calligraphy","Photography"],"question":"What is the word given to a printing process in which ink impressions are taken from a flat plate prepared with a greasy substance?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tallahassee","incorrectAnswers":["Miami","Orlando","Jacksonville"],"question":"Which city of Florida got its name from Creek words meaning 'old town'?","difficulty":"hard"},